It is the turbulent Sengoku period.
어지러운 전국 시대.
Warlords keep on fighting day and night over Jipangu State, where Karakuri people live.
카라쿠리인이 사는 지팡구국에서는 군웅할거하여 밤낮으로 접전이 계속되고
Karakuri martial artists were sharpening their swords, dreaming of victory and honor.
카라쿠리 무예가들도 승리와 영광을 꿈꾸며 맹렬히 싸우고 있었다.
And now, a wild hero has arrived, seeking to be the number one Karakuri martial artist!
그리고 지금, 카라쿠리 무예가 제일을 꿈꾸는 터무니없는 영웅이 탄생했다!
Musashi is here-dasu!
무사시 등장이오!
Karakuri Kengouden
카라쿠리 검호전: 무사시 로드
A man always dreams of the day
사내는 언제나 세계 한가운데서
in the center of the world to become
제일 강해질 날을
AH! AH! the strongest
아! 아! 꿈꿔라
Raise the sword of your heart high to the wide sky
마음의 칼을 넓은 하늘로 번쩍 쳐들어
Raise the curtain to the road of adventure
모험의 길의 막을 연다
A skilled swordsman roams on Jipangu State
지팡구국을 떠도는 검호
His name is Musashi, a Karakuri man
그 이름은 카라쿠리인 무사시
Go! Fight!
가라! 싸워라!
The sound of fierce duels
격렬한 승부의 소리는
makes life dazzling
눈부신 인생
Battles of yesterdays make you stronger today
싸웠던 어제보다도 오늘 강해진다
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
무예! 이도류 무사시
Tomorrow will be glorious
내일은 빛난다
The sound of fierce duels
격렬한 승부의 소리는
makes life dazzling
눈부신 인생
Fight the utmost with the stillness
싸우는 한껏 고요함과 함께
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
무예! 이도류 무사시
His eyes shined! Musashi!
미간이 반짝였다 무사시!!
Rikudomaoh is looking to get the sacred sword to take the world under his hands.
천하를 손에 잡기 위해 다시 성검을 노리는 육도마왕.
Megaton Castle appeared in Edotopia and put on fire, so Jiraiyan and Kerokichi had to put out the fire.
에도토피아에 나타난 메가톤성은 불을 피워, 지라이얀과 케로키치가 필사적인 소화 활동을 하고 있었다.
(Tenshukaku: lit. sky guard house; the highest tower within the castle)
(천수각: 성의 중심에서 제일 높게 만든 망루)
But Hanzō caught onto the king at the Tenshukaku of Edo Castle.
그러나 한조는 에도 성의 천수각에서 국왕을 따라잡는다.
But the power of Senhime's love managed to get rid of Hanzō and protect the king.
그렇지만 센히메의 사랑의 힘으로 불사신 한조를 퇴치하고 국왕을 지켰다.
Nikko Plan
닛코 계획
Shingen
신겐이오
The burnt field didn't last long.
타버린 벌판도 아주 잠깐이구나.
The people of Edotopia are robust.
에도토피아의 사람들은 억세구나.
Don't you agree with me, Kerokichi?
그렇치, 케로키치?
Where is Musashi?
무사시는 대체 어쨌어?
He's late. It's not like he forgot the departure time.
늦네요. 출발 시각을 잊었을 리도 없고.
Isn't it likely that he's staying at Otsuru's tea store and eating dango?
분명 오츠루네 찻집에라도 들러서 단고라도 먹는거 아녀?
Yes, that is possible.
그래, 있을 법한 일이다.
Or, it's possible that he's looking to sneak foods in the kitchen of Edo Castle.
아니, 어쩌면, 에도 성 내 부엌에서 먹을 거라도 몰래 탐내고 있는 게...
No way! Even if Musashi's gluttony is strong, he wouldn't be that endlessly stupid!
그런! 무사시가 아무리 식탐이 강하다고 해도 그렇게 한없이 멍청할 거라고는...
Well, to tell you the truth, he dared to snitch pickled radish from the leftover of Lord Ieyasu's table,
아니, 그게, 이전에 송구스럽게도 이에야스 님이 다 드신 진지에서 단무지를 훔쳐 먹어 부엌 관리인에게 크게 혼났습니다.
Are you serious?
그거 정말이야?
I'm sorry-dasu! I won't do this again-dasu!
미안하오! 다시는 하지 않소!
Good morning, Senhime and everyone.
안녕하신가, 센히메, 모두.
Good morning, grandpa!
어, 안녕, 할아버지!
Good morning.
좋은 아침입니다.
Mornin'!
아침!
Hello, Senhime. You look elegant today as always. Is that cloth popular in Edotopia recently?
안녕, 센히메 님. 오늘은 또 정취있는 모습으로. 그 옷은 최근 에도토피아에서 유행하는 것인가요.
Er, no, no, not!
에, 아니, 아니, 그런 게!
Good morning, your Highness.
좋은 아침입니다, 국왕 전하.
It's almost time. Are everyone ready?
슬슬 시각이 되었는데, 준비는 되었나?
The problem is that Musashi still isn't here.
그게, 무사시가 아직 안 왔어.
I saw him before.
어라, 아까 보았습니다만.
Yes, he went back to the village since he had something to do with Zenigatan.
그래, 제니가탄하고 일이 있어서 마을에 돌아갔다고 했다.
Where exactly in the village, when we're busy!?
이런 할 일 많을 때 마을이라니 어디에!
I guess he went to see Otsuru!
아, 또 오츠루 보러 간 거지?
No, he said that he had something to do in a place named Yaozen.
아니, 뭔가 야오젠이라고 하는 곳에 일이 있다고 했다.
Yaozen?
야오젠?
Edotopia Big Fire Recovery Ceremony - The 3rd Edotopia Eat-A-Lot Contest - Yaozen
에도토피아 대화 부흥 기념 제 3회 에도토피아 대식 대회 - 야오젠
The 3rd Edotopia Eat-A-Lot Contest will begin soon.
지금부터 제 3회 에도토피아 대식 대회를 개최하겠습니다.
What an excellent restaurant-dasu!
훌륭한 음식집이오.
Yaozen is the best restaurant in Edotopia. It's not a place that we can casually stop by.
야오젠이라고 하면 에도토피아 제일의 가게니까요. 보통은 우리 따위가 얼렁거릴 곳이 아니죠.
I've heard about this place, too.
나도 들은 거 있어.
Is it expensive-dasu?
비싸오?
Expensive or not - it costs 100 ryos for one rice with tea.
비싸니 안 비싸니, 찻밥 하나에 100량이나 한대요.
What? 100 ryos!?
어? 100량?
O- oh, excuse us!
아, 시, 실례했습니다.
(Denenchōfu: The most expensive area to live in Tokyo)
(덴엔초후: 도쿄에서 제일 살기 비싼 곳)
With 100 ryos, I can have rice with a saury and rolled eggs on it every day, in a house at Denenchofu!
100량이나 있으면 우리 집 따위는 매일 밥 위에 꽁치하고 계란말이를 위에 올려서 덴엔초후에 집을 세울 수 있지!
You have a plenty of money, since you throw them around-dasu!
돈을 던지는 걸 보면 잔뜩 있는 거잖소!
Well, there are the tools for my job! But recently, even Akane is being noisy to me, saying save money, with my tossing coins!
그건 내 직업 도구니까요. 최근은 절약, 절약 해서, 이 던지는 돈조차도 아카네가 왱왱거리고 있어요.
Ms. Akane does that? She didn't look like she would do that-dasu...
아카네 씨가? 그렇게는 안 보였소...
Akane says that she wants to stop living in a rented house and get a stand-alone house, but I'm so worthless.
아니, 그것도 이것도 지금의 셋집살이에서 빠져나와서, 독채집을 가지고 싶다고 아카네가 말하니까요. 내가 변변치 못하니.
That's problematic-dasu.
큰일이오.
Good old days! I miss my days of throwing my tossing coins to bad guys to my heart's content!
아, 옛날이 그립지. 악당 놈들에게 실컷 동전이나 던지던 그 시대가 말야!
You can throw rocks from now on-dasu!
지금부터는 돌을 던지면 되오!
Rocks are inconvenient to walk around with! Moreover, that would be throwing away the trademark of Boss Zenigatan.
돌이면 가지고 걸어다니기 불편해요! 제니가탄 두목의 트레이드마크를 버리는 것이기도 하고.
Ever since I made a home with Akane, women fans have been decreased significantly.
아, 아카네하고 가정을 꾸렸더니 어지간히 여성 팬이 줄어들었고.
You were that popular-dasu?
그렇게 인기있었소?
Of course!
그야 당연!
When I became a private detective, it was as if there was a uproar to see me!
내가 탐정이 되고 왕왕 유명해지던 때도 큰일이었지요!
Women in the village were pushing their way through infinitely,
마을 여자들, 밀어 헤쳐, 밀어 헤쳐, 밀어 헤쳐, 밀어 헤쳐,
and from a 6-year-old kiddo to 90-year-old granny were like, "Mr. Zenigatan! Mr. Zenigatan!" and it was so noisy!
어리면 6살 얘부터 늙으면 90살 할매까지 "제니가탄 님! 제니가탄 님!" 하고 참 시끄러워서 말이야!
Money makes one poor
돈 때문에라면 가난해지기도 하지
Hardships that I like are more pleasant than pleasures
좋아하는 고생이라면 낙보다도 즐거워
How boisterous!
성가시군!
Even if nothing else
다른 것을 차치하고라도
guts are most important to men
사내라면 기개가 중요해
(okappiki: private detective; used as mechappiki in the song)
(오캇피키: 탐정; 노래에서는 메캇피키)
The chivalrous mechanical detective of Edotopia
에도토피아의 메카 탐정 협객
Leave the incidents to me
사건이라면 맡겨둬
I know democracy
알고 있어 데모크라시
I'm the justice! Follow me!
내가 정의다 따라와라!
You're making me envious-dasu!
이야, 샘나오!
You know it! The good old days!
그렇죠? 옛날이 좋았지!
You're there.
있었네.
You are there.
있었네요.
What are you doing, Musashi!? It's far past the time to leave!
뭘 하고 있냐, 무사시! 나갈 시간은 훨씬 지났어!
Well, I told Lord Ieyasu that I'll be late for a bit-dasu.
아니, 잠깐 늦는다고 이에야스 님께 말씀드렸소.
You call this a bit? You made all of us wait!
뭐가 잠깐이야? 이렇게 사람 기다리게 하고!
(Disembowelment isn't enough for death, so kaishaku beheads whoever that's disemboweling oneself)
(할복만으로는 죽지 않으므로 카이샤쿠가 할복하는 자의 목을 침)
Disembowel yourself, Musashi!
할복해라, 무사시!
I'll behead!
목은 내가!
No way! You're cruel!
그런! 너무해!
Today night's Hououmaru will do a good job at cutting.
오늘밤의 봉황환은 잘 벨 것 같구나.
It's daytime now-dasu!
지금 낮이오!
I have something to say.
말씀드릴 것이 있습니다.
What is it?
뭐냐.
Ieyasu is trying to send the king and the sacred sword to Nikko in secret.
에이야스는 국왕과 성검을 남모르게 닛코에 보내려고 하고 있습니다.
What? To Nikko?
뭐라? 닛코에?
Nikko is the place where the temple for Ieyasu's ancestors are given prayers. He's trying to hide them there first.
닛코는 이에야스의 조상에게 제사를 지내는 신사가 있습니다. 일단 그곳에 숨기려는 것이겠지요.
I see. Shingen, I will entrust this job to your Track Driving Corps. Can you do it beautifully?
그래. 신겐, 그 조치, 네 궤도주행군단에 맡기겠다. 잘 할 수 있느냐?
Please leave it to me.
맡겨 주십시오.
Unlike those Dokuganryu and Hanzō....
지금까지 도쿠간류도 한조도...
Well, that's that.
뭐, 됐다.
Unlike the lowly Hanzō and Dokuganryu, with practically invincible Track Driving Corps, failure is impossible.
한조, 도쿠간류 따위와는 달리, 무적이라 불리는 궤도주행군단이 있으니 실패는 생각할 수 없습니다.
Well said!
잘 말했다!
Anyway, since they're coming out from Edo Castle, my strategy has already succeeded.
어떻든, 에도 성에서 나오다니, 내 작전은 벌써 성공한 것과 마찬가지.
Pulling the cart in travel kit again feels weird-dasu.
다시 나그네 차림으로 짐수레를 끌다니 왠지 이상하오.
It's not like we have things prepared, so it couldn't be helped!
딱히 준비된 게 없으니까 어쩔 수 없잖아?
You'll depart first for now. Please be careful in your way.
일단 먼저 출발하시겠습니다. 도중 부디 조심해 주십시오.
Yessir. I will protect Senhime's life only by myself, no matter what.
예, 저 혼자서 반드시 센히메 님의 목숨을 지켜 보이겠습니다.
Oh, yeah?
아, 그러셔?
Mr. Musashi! I'll follow you later!
무사시 씨! 나도 나중에 따라갈게요.
Roger-dasu! Since I'm here, Rikudomaoh isn't a problem-dasu!
알겠소! 내가 있는 이상 육도마왕 따위 문제가 안 되오!
Do your best, Mr. Musashi!
힘내, 무사시!
I've entrusted the sacred sword to Jūbee. I'd like to ask Your Highness and Shotoku to get inside that box.
성검은 주베에게 맡겨 두었습니다. 국왕 전하와 쇼토쿠 님은 저 상자에 들어가 주시길 바랍니다.
The Highness, in that box!?
저 상자에 국왕 전하를!?
Please endure until we reach Nikko.
닛코에 갈 때까지 참으세요.
No, but...
아니, 그래도...
We do not know when will Edo Castle be attacked. This is the chance.
언제 에도 성이 공격당할지 모릅니다. 이 틈에.
Mr. Shotoku, please get into the box immediately.
자, 쇼토쿠 님도 어서 상자 속에.
Me too?
저도입니까?
Of course!
당연!
A journey inside a box also is a brief entertainment. Let's get in, Shotoku.
상자에 들어가서 여행하는 것도 일흥. 자, 들어가자, 쇼토쿠.
Understood. But these people are not enough in cases we got found out.
예. 그러나 만에 하나 발각되었을 때, 이 인원으로는 부족하기 그지없음이...
No, no, if we send too many people, it is so suspicious that they'll immediately find out.
아니아니, 사람이 너무 많으면 수상해서 들키고 맙니다.
You're worried a lot, Shotoku. Leave everything to Senhime and others.
걱정이 많구나, 쇼토쿠. 모든 건 센히메 일행에게 맡겨.
Understood.
예.
Depart!
자, 출발!
We'll do our best-dasu!
힘내겠소.
Disguising is unnecessary.
어차피 변장한다고 해도 소용없는 짓.
Disguised as travellers, Musashi and others headed to north, and entered the Nikko Highway.
여행자로 변장한 무사시 일행은 북으로, 북으로 향해, 닛코 가도에 들어섰다.
They were passing through without any incident, to the extent it's uncanny.
기분 나쁠 정도로 아무 일도 없이 무사하게 지나가고 있었다.
But...
그렇지만.
Are you okay, your Highness? Aren't you tired?
괜찮아요, 국왕 전하? 힘들지 않으세요?
It's alright. It's even pleasant.
괜찮아. 꽤 쾌적해.
If you have something uncomfortable, please tell me right away.
만약 뭔가 있으시면 바로 알려 주세요.
M- my back has problems! It's too narrow here!
나, 나는 허리가! 이 갑갑함은 좀!
Oh, I see.
아, 그래요.
Hey...
저기.
Senhime, let's hurry. We're planning to go over Tone River before the sun sets.
센히메 님. 서두릅시다. 오늘 중으로 도네 강은 넘어갈 생각입니다.
(1 ri: 3.9km, 20 ris: 78km; 48.5mi)
어? 도네 강이라니, 아직 지금부터 200리나 가야 하잖아! 무리야!
Impossible or not, it's dangerous to be sluggish over here. Hurry.
무리라도 꾸물대고 있으면 위험합니다. 자.
I'm tired! I'm exhausted! I'll get blistered! I'm hungry!
힘들어! 지쳤어! 물집이 생겨! 배고파!
Don't you agree, Musashi?
그렇지, 무사시?
I'm okay-dasu! I took a lot of lunch boxes-dasu!
괜찮소! 도시락 잔뜩 가져왔으니까!
Oh, I see.
아, 그래.
Stop advancing!
전진 중단!
Everyone, into offensive setup!
전원 공격 태세!
Distance 200!
거리 200!
The life of the king is at stake! Wait for the stormy latter half!
국왕의 목숨이 위험하다! 질풍노도의 후반을 기다려라!
Karakuri Kengouden: Musashi Road
카라쿠리 검호전 무사시 로드
Open fire!
쏴라!
Now sailing off-dasu!
배를 보내오!
Cannons!
대포인가!
This isn't good.
이대로는 안 되겠어.
Sir!
나리!
I took this!
가져왔수!
Great!
좋다!
What's the problem? Can't you even counterattack?
뭐가 문제냐, 반격도 못 하냐?
Did you think that you could escape my Track Driving Corps by hiding at a place like that? You fools!
그런 곳에 숨어서 우리 궤도주행군단에게서 도망칠 수 있다 생각했냐? 멍청한 놈들이!
Track Driving Corps?
궤도주행군단?
What's that-dasu!?
뭣이오, 그게!?
Don't you know Shingen, whom everyone gets reminded of, when one says Rikudomaoh's subordinate!?
모르냐! 나느 육도마왕의 부하 하면 누구나 아는 신겐이다!
Shingen?
신겐?
What? Shingen? I know smidgen-dasu!
어? 신겐? 중원이라면 알고 있소.
You brat must be Musashi!
네놈 무사시렷다!
That's right-dasu! I'm that famous Musashi from Miyamoto village of Niten'ichiryū-dasu!
그렇소! 내가 유명한 이천일류, 미야모토 마을의 무사시이오!
You brat! I see that you're too elated for me to play with!
네이놈! 잠깐 놀아주려 했더니 기고만장해가지고는! 국왕과 성검을 넘기면 넘어가지만 그리하지 않으면 모두 불바다에 빠트린다!
You're the one to sink into the sea of fire!
불바다에 빠지는 건 네놈이다!
A child's magic doesn't work against me, Shingen! Open fire!
이 신겐에게 얘들 장난같은 요술은 안 통한다! 쏴라!
Do you think you can do something with this, Mr. Zenigatan?
어떻게든 될 것 같습니까, 제니가탄 님.
Leave it to me.
맡겨 주쇼.
Huh? That's weird.
어라? 이상하네.
Hey! What's wrong? Hey!
어이! 왜 그래! 어이!
That was easy.
별 거 아니네.
Now, sir, hurry!
자, 나리, 어서!
Right.
좋습니다.
Anyway, this is one interesting machinery!
그래도 이건 대단한 장치네요!
Do you think you can operate?
움직일 수 있겠습니까.
Leave it to me. I'm pretty confident when it comes to machinery.
맡겨 주쇼. 장치에 대해선 쫌 자신이 있으니.
So, this must be it!
그래, 이거구나!
We're going!
갑니다!
Please do so.
부탁드립니다.
Do not get out from the line, you fool!
대열에서 벗어나지 마라, 멍청아!
What!?
뭐야!?
oh my god!
오 마이 갓!
What's going on?
뭔 일이야, 대체?
I don't know-dasu. Let's run using this chance-dasu!
잘 모르겠소. 이 틈에 달아나오!
You bastard! Get that traitors! Get them!
네이놈! 배신자를 쫒아라! 쫒아!
Damn!
제기랄!
It's a failure for now, since they hid into the mountain. But still, they're nothing more than rats without a place to hide.
산에 도망치다니 실패구나. 뭐, 어차피 달아날 곳 없는 쥐와 다를 게 없지.
We'll do an all-out attack tomorrow morning. Assume that your life ends then!
내일 아침 총공격해 주겠다. 목숨이 거기까지인줄 알아라!
How do you call this?
이건 뭐라 하나?
Those are roasted dangos.
구운 단고라 합니다.
They're pretty delicious.
꽤 맛있는 것이구나.
Great to know that you like these.
입에 맞으니 다행이요.
Otsuru's roasted dangos are the best of jipang-dasu.
오츠루의 구운 단고는 지팡구 제일이오.
These are pretty delicious!
이야, 꽤나 맛있어.
Huh? Where's Kojirō, by the way-dasu?
어라? 그러고 보니 코지로는 어디 갔소?
He's working as a guard.
지금 망을 보고 있어요.
Then I'll go give him dangos.
그럼 내가 단고 가져다 주고 올게.
Senhime, you're really kind.
센히메 님은 정말 마음이 착하시네요.
Oh, my!
아, 그런!
Oh, my. They'll be fine if I blow off dusts!
어라, 저런. 먼지 불어내면 괜찮아.
He won't die.
죽지는 않아.
To a lonely strong man,
고독한 강한 사내는
even winning
이기는 일마저도
is painful
쓰라려지지
A lonely tender man
고독한 고운 사내는
becomes cold
사랑하는 사람에게는
to lovers
차가워지지
Shaking in darkness, City Light
어둠에 흔들리는 도시 불빛
The tide of the world isn't following my will
뜻대로 안 되는 세상 풍조
Like a swallow in the blue sky
파란 하늘의 제비처럼
Cutting through the wind
바람을 갈라
I'm a swallow flying through the disordered sky
요동치는 하늘길을 날아가는 제비
Swallow in the blue sky
파란 하늘의 제비
On all one's own
혼자서
Until the day that another lonely bird
언젠가 또다른 외로운 새가
gets ahead of me
앞질러가는 그 날까지
Ah, Senhime, you were listening to my song? How embarassing...
아, 센히메 님. 듣고 계셨습니까. 부끄...
Aren't you good, Kojirō?
잘 하잖아, 코지로?
I often use karaoke boxes...
종종 상자노래방에 가니까요...
Here! Have some dangos!
여기, 단고 먹어!
Yes! Thank you!
네! 잘 먹겠습니다!
There're stones in dangos...
단고에 돌이...
Really? How could that be? That's weird!
그래? 왜일까, 이상하네!
By the way, Mr. Jūbee...
그런데, 주베 님.
How we are going to slip out from now on?
지금부터 어떻게 빠져나갈 생각입니까.
We can't possibly win with only one tank.
전차 하나로는 이길 턱이 없으니 말이죠.
That's it-dasu! We'll get everyone onto the tank and run-dasu!
그렇소! 다들 전차에 태우고 달아나오!
But it's not like everyone can get onto that tank.
그래도 그 전차에 모두 탈 수 있는 건 아니야.
No-dasu! Listen to my idea-dasu!
아니오! 내 생각을 들어 보시오!
Lord Shingen! Look at that!
신겐 님! 저걸!
Everyone, sortie formation!
전원 출격 태세!
Those fools. We'll just snipe them!
멍청한 놈들. 노려 쏠 뿐이다!
Open fire!
쏴라!
Lord Shingen. Bringing them down is only a matter of time.
신겐 님. 숨통을 끊어 놓는 것도 시간의 문제군요.
Yes, but I didn't think that they would choose such a foolish way of running...
그래. 그래도 이렇게 멍청하게 도망가다니...
Huh?
어?
It seems that our plan has worked-dasu.
보아하니 작전은 성공한 듯 하오.
You did it!
해냈구나!
I knew it was a trickery.
역시 속임수였군.
Shingen! I must praise you for finding that out, even though you're our enemy!
신겐! 적이지만 잘 알아냈다!
True-dasu!
정말이오!
King! I'll take your life!
국왕! 목숨은 잘 가져가겠다!
Wait a moment-dasu! Shingen, I want an one-to-one fight-dasu!
잠깐 기다리시오, 신겐! 1:1의 승부를 바라오!
What!?
뭣이!?
If I win, let us just go-dasu!
만약 내가 이기면 우리를 보내주시오!
What if you lose?
지면?
We do not lose.
지지는 않소.
Grab your sword, Musashi!
칼 들어라, 무사시!
I was just about to do that-dasu!
바라던 바이오!
You're pretty good, Musashi.
꽤 하는구나, 무사시.
Shingen, you too-dasu.
신겐이야말로이오.
I got you-dasu!
잡았소!
That's cowardly! It's an one-to-one fight!
비겁하오! 1:1 승부이오!
I never promised you that!
그런 거 난 약속 안 했다!
Then you must be fine with we facing you!
그럼 우리가 상대해 주어도 괜찮겠지?
Shingen, face us!
신겐, 달려들어라!
How cowardly!
비겁해!
This is it for today!
오늘은 이쯤에서 해 두겠다!
Pfft!
메롱!
Thanks to the great activities of Musashi and others, the king managed to reach Nikko safely.
무사시 일행의 대활약으로 국왕 일행은 무사하게 닛코에 겨우 도착했다.
But Musashi made a resolution to himself
그렇지만 무사시는 다음에 신겐과 대면하는 때, 그 때야말로 이 강적과 우열을 가려야 할 것이라고 각오를 했다.
A strong man can recognize another strong man.
강한 사내는 강한 사내를 알아보는 법이었다.
I fought and I got beaten
싸우고 맞았어
Nosebleed drips rendezvous
코피 쓩이야 랑데부
I can't lose, so take my blow!
나도 지지 않으려 한발!
Pinch! Punch! I won by reversal
핀치 펀치로 대역전
Next is delightful lunchtime
다음 시간 즐거운
But it's not delightful today
급식일 텐데
The thunder of my teacher
선생님의 벼락이
only hit me and nobody else
나한테만 떨어져 왔어
I tried to explain
사정을 말해도
But he won't listen
들어주지 않는 채
Now whatever I do
어떻게 해도 역시
I end up crying
눈물이 나오고 말아
Don't cry when you eat, or
울면서 밥먹으면
it tastes totally bad
완전 맛없어
you'll feel downhearted
왠지 안타까워
Chasing Megaton Castle, we headed to Seto Inland Sea-dasu.
메가톤성을 쫒아 우리는 세토 내해로 향했소.
But Otsuru followed us and is doing women's quarrel with Osenchan.
그런데 오츠루가 뒤를 쫒아와서 오센짱하고 여자의 다툼.
At that time, Osenchan fell into Hanzō's trap and was caught-dasu.
그 때, 오센짱이 한조의 함정에 빠져 잡히고 말았소.
Damn! I have to do something about this-dasu!
젠장! 이건 어떻게든 해야 하오!
Next story! The Wooden Horse was a Trap
다음 이야기! 목마는 무서운 함정이었소
It's the stormy Otsuru-dasu!
질풍노도의 오츠루이오!
Next Episode
다음 이야기
The Wooden Horse
목마는 무서운
was a Trap
함정이었소
Look forwards for it!
기대하세요!